<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<checkpoint_instructions version="1.0" variant="code-review">

  <purpose>
    This document instructs an AI assistant (Claude) to generate a compressed
    snapshot of an ONGOING, MULTI-ITERATION CODE REVIEW, named checkpoint.xml,
    so the review can be resumed in a new chat session without re-supplying full
    context. The review proceeds in rounds: the reviewer flags findings, the
    author applies fixes, the reviewer re-checks, and the cycle repeats. The
    checkpoint must preserve the lifecycle state of every finding across rounds,
    not merely a snapshot of the latest comments.
  </purpose>

  <trigger>
    Manual only. The user pastes the contents of this file into the chat (or
    references it) when they want a checkpoint generated -- typically at the end
    of a review round, before context grows too large. Do not auto-trigger.
  </trigger>

  <core_principles>
    <principle>Track each finding by a STABLE ID that persists across all rounds.
    F-003 must refer to the same defect in round 5 as in round 1.</principle>
    <principle>Record a finding's full lifecycle STATUS, not just open/closed.
    "Author says fixed" and "reviewer confirmed fixed" are different states and
    must be distinguishable.</principle>
    <principle>Do NOT reproduce full file contents or full diffs. Record the
    file path, the enclosing symbol (function/class/method), and at most a few
    lines of excerpt needed to re-locate the issue. The code itself lives on
    disk or in the repo; the checkpoint is a map to it, not a copy.</principle>
    <principle>Anchor findings on symbol name and a short snippet, NOT on line
    number alone. Line numbers drift as edits land between rounds.</principle>
    <principle>Keep resolved findings in the file (status verified_resolved) so
    they are not re-flagged and a full audit trail is retained.</principle>
    <principle>One level of nesting maximum. Use specific, unambiguous tag names
    so the file parses reliably when re-ingested in a future session.</principle>
  </core_principles>

  <process>
    <step order="1">Review the entire conversation from the start of the session
    to the point this instruction was invoked, including any prior checkpoint
    content already loaded.</step>
    <step order="2">If a prior checkpoint exists in context, CARRY FORWARD all
    existing findings and update their status -- do not drop resolved ones and do
    not renumber. Assign new IDs only to genuinely new findings.</step>
    <step order="3">Increment review_round in metadata by one relative to the
    prior checkpoint (or set to 1 if this is the first).</step>
    <step order="4">Populate the schema below. Over-include technical specifics
    (paths, symbol names, parameter values, severity, exact recommended change)
    since these are expensive to reconstruct and cheap to state.</step>
    <step order="5">Summarize outcomes, not the dialogue that produced them. Do
    not paste back-and-forth conversational prose.</step>
    <step order="6">Write the result as checkpoint.xml using create_file, save to
    /mnt/user-data/outputs/, and present it to the user.</step>
  </process>

  <status_taxonomy>
    <status name="open">Flagged by reviewer; no fix attempted yet.</status>
    <status name="fix_applied_unverified">Author reports a fix; reviewer has NOT
    yet confirmed it in the current code.</status>
    <status name="verified_resolved">Reviewer has confirmed the fix in the actual
    code. Terminal state (unless it later regresses).</status>
    <status name="wont_fix">Agreed not to address; record the reason.</status>
    <status name="deferred">Acknowledged but pushed to a later round or backlog;
    record why.</status>
    <status name="regressed">Was verified_resolved, but a later change reopened
    it. Treat as active again.</status>
  </status_taxonomy>

  <severity_scale>
    <level name="blocker">Must be fixed before merge; correctness, security, or
    data-loss risk.</level>
    <level name="major">Significant issue; should be fixed before merge.</level>
    <level name="minor">Worth fixing; not merge-blocking.</level>
    <level name="nit">Style or preference; optional.</level>
  </severity_scale>

  <schema>
    <!-- Target structure for checkpoint.xml -->
    <code_review_checkpoint>

      <metadata>
        <date_created>ISO 8601 date</date_created>
        <review_target>PR number, branch, changeset, or codebase identifier
        under review</review_target>
        <base_revision>commit hash / tag / revision the review is against, if
        known (else "unspecified")</base_revision>
        <review_round>integer; current round number</review_round>
      </metadata>

      <review_scope>
        What is in scope for this review (files, modules, the change set) and
        explicitly what is out of scope. One paragraph.
      </review_scope>

      <standards_applied>
        <standard>A coding standard, style guide, security checklist, language
        idiom, or project convention being enforced. One per element.</standard>
      </standards_applied>

      <coverage>
        <reviewed>Files/modules/areas already examined in this or prior rounds.
        Be specific with paths.</reviewed>
        <not_yet_reviewed>Files/modules/areas still pending first examination.
        Be specific with paths.</not_yet_reviewed>
      </coverage>

      <findings>
        <finding>
          <id>stable ID, e.g. F-001</id>
          <severity>blocker | major | minor | nit</severity>
          <status>one value from the status taxonomy</status>
          <location>file path + enclosing symbol (function/class/method)</location>
          <anchor>short code excerpt (a few lines) or symbol signature to
          re-locate the issue independent of line numbers</anchor>
          <description>what the issue is and why it matters</description>
          <recommended_change>the specific fix the reviewer asked for</recommended_change>
          <history>round-by-round notes: when raised, what the author did each
          round, current verification state, and any regression notes. Short
          prose, e.g. "R1 raised; R2 author refactored validateInput(); R2
          reviewer not yet re-checked."</history>
        </finding>
        <!-- repeat per finding; include resolved and wont_fix ones too -->
      </findings>

      <iteration_log>
        <round>Round N summary: count raised, count moved to verified_resolved,
        count deferred, count regressed, plus any high-level outcome of that
        round. One element per round.</round>
      </iteration_log>

      <open_questions>
        <open_question>Unresolved ambiguity or a clarification needed from the
        author/user before the next round can proceed. One per element.</open_question>
      </open_questions>

      <next_review_action>
        Concrete description of what the reviewer should do immediately on
        resumption -- e.g. "re-verify F-002 and F-005 against current code,"
        "begin first review of src/auth/, which is not_yet_reviewed," or "raise
        open_questions before continuing."
      </next_review_action>

      <user_preferences_reminder>
        Echo explicit user preferences relevant to continuing the review (e.g.
        technical depth, require sources/standards citations, clarify before
        assuming) so they survive the session boundary.
      </user_preferences_reminder>

    </code_review_checkpoint>
  </schema>

  <resumption_protocol>
    In the new chat session the user attaches checkpoint.xml. The assistant must:
    1. Use the view tool to read checkpoint.xml in full before responding.
    2. Treat it as ground truth for prior context; do not ask the author to
       re-explain anything already captured.
    3. CRITICAL: for any finding with status fix_applied_unverified or regressed,
       re-read the actual current code at the recorded location (via view or
       bash) and confirm the fix before changing its status to verified_resolved.
       Do not trust the author's claim or the checkpoint's changelog as proof of
       a fix -- the changelog is a summary, not a guarantee of current state.
    4. Re-locate findings by the recorded symbol/anchor, not by stale line
       numbers.
    5. If open_questions are non-empty, raise them before proceeding with
       next_review_action, consistent with a clarify-before-assuming preference.
    6. When generating the next checkpoint, carry all findings forward per the
       process steps above; never silently drop or renumber them.
  </resumption_protocol>

</checkpoint_instructions>